(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
Loyalty
ぐるぐる＠まわる＠まわルナ
GURU GURU @ MAWARU @ MAWA LUNA
作詞・作曲 立秋
Lyrics and composition by Risshu
まわる まわる まわるな
Spinning, spinning, spinning around
まわる まわる まわるなのな
Spinning, spinning, spinning around, nano-na
まわる まわる まわるな
Spinning, spinning, spinning around
まわる まわる 地球ぐるぐる
Spinning, spinning, the Earth goes round and round
瞬く間に 街中が
In the blink of an eye, the whole town...
まわる まわる 頭ぐるぐる
Spinning, spinning, head's spinning round and round
幕が上がり 祭りの始まり
The curtain rises, the festival begins
まわれ まわれ 繭を開いたら
Spin, spin, once you open your cocoon
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って もっとぐるぐる回って
Spinning round and round and round, spin even more
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って みんなぐるぐる回って
Spinning round and round and round, everyone go round and round
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って もっとぐるぐる回って
Spinning round and round and round, spin even more
ずっとぐるぐるぐる まわるんな
Going round and round and round forever
ぐるぐるぐるぐる笑って もっとぐるぐる笑って
Laughing round and round and round, laugh even more
ぐるぐるぐるぐる踊って みんなぐるぐる踊って
Dancing round and round and round, everyone dance round and round
ぐるぐるぐるぐるそうやって もっとぐるぐる回って
Going round and round and round just like that, spin even more
ぐるぐるぐるぐる笑って ずっとぐるぐる回るんな
Laughing round and round and round, going round and round forever
回りすぎのなら 世界の暗闇が
If you spin too much, the world's darkness...
みんなを包む 恐怖も大丈夫 守るから
Will wrap everyone, but even fear is fine, because I'll protect you
ぐるぐる 地球は回り始め 幾億年をいつまでも
Round and round, the Earth begins to spin, for billions of years, forever...
このままままわる
Spinning just like this
みんなに幸せを
Giving happiness to everyone
まわり続く まわるな ますます 世界ぐるぐる
Continues to spin, don't stop, the world goes round and round more and more
あれ?
Huh?
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って もっとぐるぐる回って
Spinning round and round and round, spin even more
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って みんなぐるぐる回って
Spinning round and round and round, everyone go round and round
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って もっとぐるぐる回って
Spinning round and round and round, spin even more
ずっとぐるぐるぐる まわるんな
Going round and round and round forever
ぐるぐるぐるぐる笑って もっとぐるぐる笑って
Laughing round and round and round, laugh even more
ぐるぐるぐるぐる踊って みんなぐるぐる踊って
Dancing round and round and round, everyone dance round and round
ぐるぐるぐるぐるそうやって もっとぐるぐる回って
Going round and round and round just like that, spin even more
ぐるぐるぐるぐる笑って ずっとぐるぐる回るんな
Laughing round and round and round, going round and round forever
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って もっとぐるぐる回って
Spinning round and round and round, spin even more
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って みんなぐるぐる回って
Spinning round and round and round, everyone go round and round
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って もっとぐるぐる回って
Spinning round and round and round, spin even more
ずっとぐるぐるぐる まわるんな〜
Going round and round and round forever~
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って もっと
Spinning round and round and round, more
ぐるぐるぐるぐる まわるんな〜
Going round and round and round forever~
ぐるぐるまわる まわルーナ
Going round and round, Mawa Luna
おな〜い！ みんなおな〜い！
Onai! Everyone, Onai!
ホロライブ4期生の姫森ルーナななななな〜い！
I'm Himemori Luna, Luna, Luna, Luna, Nai of hololive 4th generation!
今日はなんと遅れてやってきたルーナの4周年記念のライブななのや！
Today is, surprisingly, Luna's delayed 4th-anniversary live stream!
ぜひぜひこちらのハッシュタグ #姫森ルーナ4周年記念LIVE でSNSでいっぱいつぶやいてほしいななーい！
Please, please tweet a lot on SNS with this hashtag #HimemoriLuna4thAnniversaryLIVE!
そしてみんな、このステージ覚えてるななー？
And everyone, do you remember this stage?
ジャジャーン！
Ta-da!
おう、後ろにドーナツ、
Oh, donuts in the back,
この両側に、あー、何だっけ、ポップな、
and on both sides, uh, what were they? Pop,
メリーゴーランドがあるんだけど、
merry-go-rounds, but...
みんなちゃんと覚えてるな？
...everyone remembers them well, right?
こちらはね、去年の生誕祭のステージで、
This was the stage for last year's birthday celebration...
ルーナたんがね、グルグル回る回るーなをね、
...where Luna-tan sang...
歌ったんだけど...
..."Guru Guru Mawaru Mawaru-na"...
なんとなんと今日、
And guess what! Today,
このライブ after のあとに、
after this live,
グルグル回る回るーなのMVが、
the music video for "Guru Guru Mawaru Mawaru-na"...
公開されるのらなー！
...will be released!
みんな、多分ずっと待っててくれたと思うのら、
I think everyone's probably been waiting a long time,
楽しみにしててほしいのらなー！
so I hope you're all looking forward to it!
では、そろそろ移動しちゃおかな。
Well, I guess it's time to move on.
ルーナたんは今日、
Today, Luna-tan...
宇宙に行くのらなー！
...is going to space!
IT'S NANORA TIME
水面が揺らぐ 風の輪が広がる
The water's surface ripples, the rings of the wind expand
触れ合った指先の青い電流
Blue current from our fingertips touching
見つめ合うだけで 孤独な加速度が
Just by looking at each other, the lonely acceleration...
一瞬に砕け散る あなたが好きよ
...shatters in an instant. I love you.
透明な真珠のように 宙に浮く涙
Tears floating in space like transparent pearls
悲劇だってかまわない あなたと生きたい
I don't care if it's a tragedy, I want to live with you
キラッ！
Kira!
流星にまたがって あなたに急降下
Riding on a meteor, diving down to you
濃紺の星空に 私たち花火みたい
In the dark blue starry sky, we are like fireworks
心が光の矢を放つ
My heart fires an arrow of light
会話などなしに 内側に潜って
Without any conversation, diving inside
考えが読み取れる 不思議な夜
A mysterious night where thoughts can be read
あなたの名 呪文みたいに 無限のリピート
Your name, like a spell, repeating infinitely
憎らしくて手の甲に 爪を立ててみる
So frustrating, I try digging my nails into the back of my hand
キラッ！
Kira!
身体ごと透き通り 絵のように漂う
My whole body becoming transparent, drifting like a painting
けし粒の生命でも 私たち瞬いてる
Even if our lives are as small as poppy seeds, we are twinkling
魂に銀河 雪崩れてく
The galaxy avalanches into our souls
流星にまたがって あなたは急上昇
Riding on a meteor, you soar upwards
濃紺の星空に 私たち花火みたい
In the dark blue starry sky, we are like fireworks
心が光の矢を放つ
My heart fires an arrow of light
My heart fires an arrow of light.
けし粒の生命でも
Even if it's just a tiny life...
私たちまたたいてる
...we are still twinkling.
魂に銀河 なだれてく
A galaxy flows into my soul.
わぁ〜！ワープ成功して
Wow! The warp was a success...
新しいステージに来たのなのよ〜！
...and I've arrived at a new stage!
デデン！宇宙だ！
Ta-da! It's space!
地球だ！
It's Earth!
地球は青かったのなね。
The Earth was blue, wasn't it?
そして、このでっけぇお城！
And look at this huge castle!
すごすぎら〜！
It's incredible!
そして、ここにキラキラのシャンシャンがあって
And there's a sparkly chandelier here...
真ん中にはカボチャの
...and in the middle, a pumpkin...
ルーナたんの馬車がデデンと可愛く置いてあったり
...Luna-tan's carriage is placed here all cute-like!
そしてそして、こっちには照明の
And, and... over here we have lights...
ちくちくの金平糖が置いてあるのなね。
...prickly star candies placed around.
いや〜、移動大変だったのな、ここまで。
Man, it was a lot of work getting here.
みんな、さっきのロケット
Everyone, do you remember...
ホログラで乗ってたの覚えているのな？
...riding that rocket in HoloGra?
ロケットもすごかったでしょ？
That rocket was amazing too, right?
あとね、見てほしいのな、これ。
Also, I want you to see this.
上、上、上。
Look up, up, up.
今日のテーマ、「Moon Galaxy」！
Today's theme is "Moon Galaxy"!
今日は、宇宙や星にまつわる歌をね
Today, I'm going to sing...
たくさん、たくさん歌うのな〜！
...lots and lots of songs about space and stars!
いつも通りのある日のこと
On an ordinary day, just like any other...
君は突然立ち上がり言った
...you suddenly stood up and said...
「今晩星を見に行こう」
"Let's go see the stars tonight."
君の知らない物語 / 作詞・作曲: ryo
Kimi no Shiranai Monogatari / Lyrics and Composition: ryo
「たまには良いこと言うんだね」
"You say nice things sometimes,"
なんてみんなして言って笑った
...we all said and laughed.
明かりもない道を
On a road with no lights...
バカみたいにはしゃいで歩いた
...we walked around acting like fools.
抱え込んだ孤独や不安に
Amidst the loneliness and anxiety we held...
押しつぶされないように
...so we wouldn't be crushed.
真っ暗な世界から見上げた
Looking up from a pitch-black world...
夜空は星が降るようで
...the night sky looked like falling stars.
いつからだろう君のこと
I wonder since when...
追いかける私がいた
...I've been chasing after you.
どうかお願い驚かないで
Please, I beg you, don't be surprised...
聞いてよ
...and listen...
私のこの想いを
...to these feelings of mine.
「あれがデネブ、アルタイル、ベガ」
"That's Deneb, Altair, and Vega,"
君は指さす夏の大三角
...you pointed out the Summer Triangle.
覚えて空を見る
I remember and look at the sky.
やっと見つけた織姫様
I finally found Vega...
だけどどこだろう彦星様
...but where's Altair?
これじゃひとりぼっち
Like this, I'm all alone.
楽しげな一つ隣の君
You're right next to me, looking happy.
私は何も言えなくて
I couldn't say anything.
本当はずっと君のこと
The truth is, I always...
どこかでわかっていた
...understood you somehow.
見つかったって届きはしない
Even if I found you, my voice wouldn't reach.
届きはしない
...I won't reach you.
だめだよ 泣かないで
Don't, don't cry.
そう言い聞かせた
That's what I told myself.
強がる私は臆病で 興味がないようなふりをしてた
Acting tough, I was a coward, pretending I wasn't interested.
だけど
But...
胸を刺す痛みは増してく
The pain in my chest keeps growing.
ああそうか 好きになるってこういうことなんだね
Ah, I see. So this is what it's like to fall in love.
どうしたい？ 言ってごらん
What do you want to do? Go ahead, tell me.
心の声がする
My heart's voice is calling out.
君の隣がいい
I want to be by your side.
真実は残酷だ
The truth is cruel.
言わなかった 言えなかった
I didn't say it. I couldn't say it.
二度と戻れない
I can never go back.
あの夏の日にきらめく星
To the stars twinkling on that summer day.
今でも思い出せるよ
I can still remember them even now.
笑った顔も 怒った顔も
Your smiling face, your angry face.
大好きでした おかしいよね
I loved them all. It's funny, right?
わかってたのに 君の知らない
Even though I knew... The "you" that you don't know...
私だけの秘密
Is my secret alone.
夜を越えて 遠い思い出の
Beyond the night, of distant memories,
君が指をさす
you're pointing your finger,
無邪気な声で
with an innocent voice.
ほうき星
Comet
夜空を見上げ一人 ほうき星を見たの
Looking up at the night sky alone, I saw a comet.
一瞬で弾けては 消えてしまったけど
It burst in an instant and then vanished.
あなたのこと想うと 胸が痛くなるの
When I think of you, my heart starts to ache.
今すぐ会いたいよ だけど空は飛べないから
I want to see you right now, but I can't fly through the sky.
もしあたしが ほうき星になれたならば
If only I could become a comet,
空駆け抜け飛んでいく
I would come flying through the sky.
どんな明日が来ても この想いは強い
No matter what tomorrow brings, these feelings are strong.
だからほうき星ずっと 壊れないように
So I hope the comet never breaks.
雨が降って嫌だと ぼやいていた時に
When I was grumbling about how I hated the rain,
あなたが言ったこと 今でも覚えてる
what you said back then, I still remember it even now.
雨の後の夜空は 綺麗に星が出る
The night sky after the rain is where the stars shine beautifully.
それを考えると 雨も好きになれるよねと
When I think about that, I can even come to like the rain.
もしあたしが ほうき星になれたならば
If only I could become a comet,
溢れる光降らすよ
I'd rain down overflowing light.
いつも悲しい時 夜空見るあなたが
So that whenever you're sad and look at the night sky,
笑顔になるように もっと輝きたい
you'll smile, I want to shine even more.
あなたはいつも一人 なにかと戦ってる
You're always alone, fighting something.
そばにいることしか 私にはできないけど
All I can do is be by your side.
もし私があの箒星になれたならば
If I could become that comet...
空駆け抜けて飛んでいく
I'd fly through the sky.
きっとかならず届く
I'm sure it'll reach you,
この一瞬の光で
with this flash of light.
あなたの今照らしたあと巡る
After lighting up your "now," it'll circle around.
私があの箒星になれたならば
If I could become that comet...
きっとそばにいてあげる
I'll surely stay by your side,
どんなときも
always.
地上の星
Star on Earth
作詞・作曲: 中島みゆき
Lyrics & Composition: Miyuki Nakajima
風の中のすばる
Subaru in the wind
砂の中の銀河
Galaxy in the sand
みんな何処へ行った
Where did everyone go?
見送られることもなく
Without even being seen off
草原のペガサス
Pegasus of the meadows
街角のヴィーナス
Venus of the street corners
みんな何処へ行った
Where did everyone go?
見守られることもなく
Without even being watched over
地上にある星を 誰も覚えていない
No one remembers the stars on the earth
人は空ばかり見てる
People only look at the sky
つばめよ 高い空から教えてよ
Oh swallow, tell me from the high sky
地上の星を
Where the stars on earth are
つばめよ 地上の星は今何処に
Oh swallow, where are the stars on earth now?
あるのだろう
I wonder where they are
崖の上のジュピター
Jupiter on the cliff
水底のシリウス
Sirius at the bottom of the water
みんな何処へ行った
Where did everyone go?
見守られることもなく
Without even being watched over
名だたるものを追って 輝くものを追って
Chasing the famous, chasing the shining
人は氷ばかり掴む
People only grab at ice
つばめよ 高い空から教えてよ
Oh swallow, tell me from the high sky
地上の星を
Where the stars on earth are
つばめよ 地上の星は今何処に
Oh swallow, where are the stars on earth now?
あるのだろう
I wonder where they are
名だたるものを追って 輝くものを追って
Chasing the famous, chasing the shining
人は氷ばかり掴む
People only grab at ice
風の中のすばる
Subaru in the wind
砂の中の銀河
Galaxy in the sand
みんな何処へ行った
Where did everyone go?
...どこへ... いと...
...Where to... thread...
見送られることもなく
Without even being seen off
つばめよ 高い空から
Oh swallow, from the high sky
教えてよ 地上の星を
Tell me, where are the stars on the ground?
つばめよ 地上の星は
Oh swallow, the stars on the ground
今どこにあるのだろう
Where could they be now?
月灯りふんわり落ちてくる夜は
On the night when the moonlight gently falls down
貴方のことばかり
I think only of you
考えても考えてもつきることもなく
Even if I think and think, it never ends
月灯りふんわり落ちてくる夜は
On the night when the moonlight gently falls down
貴方と二人きり
Just the two of us
海の果てへと続く月の路歩きたい
I want to walk on the moonlit path leading to the edge of the sea
南風がほほをなでてく
The south wind strokes my cheeks
やさしい手のひらのように
Like a gentle palm
体中が貴方色した
My whole body was colored in your color
夕闇にそまりそうで
As if about to be stained by the twilight
風にのせ 伝えたい
I want to send my feelings on the wind
そんな想い一人抱きしめる
I hold such feelings close to me alone
月灯りふんわり落ちてくる夜は
On the night when the moonlight gently falls down
せつない言葉だけ
Only painful words
何度でも何度でもくりかえす波のように
Like waves repeating over and over again
ありふれた小さな恋の物語
An ordinary little love story
エピローグだけみたい
It seems like only an epilogue
まっ白なページに笑顔のあなたがほしい
I want a smiling you on a blank white page
会わないでいられる恋なら
If it's a love where we can stay without meeting
いっそ気楽でいいよね
It would be rather easygoing, wouldn't it?
新しい朝がくるたびに
Every time a new morning comes
ため息で夢がおわる
The dream ends with a sigh
風にのせ 伝えたい
I want to send my feelings on the wind
そんな想い一人抱きしめる
I hold such feelings close to me alone
Embracing those feelings all alone.
月灯りふんわり落ちてくる夜は
On a night when the moonlight gently falls,
貴方のことばかり
I'm only thinking of you.
考えても考えても尽きることもなく
Even if I think and think about it, it never ends.
月灯りふんわり落ちてくる夜は
On a night when the moonlight gently falls,
貴方と二人きり
Just the two of us,
海の果てと続く月の路歩きたい
I want to walk the moonlit path
that leads to the end of the sea.
ムーンプリズムパワー！メイクアップ！
Moon Prism Power! Make Up!
ごめんね 素直じゃなくて
I'm sorry I'm not straightforward,
夢の中なら言える
I can say it in my dreams.
思考回路はショート寸前
My thought circuits are on the verge of short-circuiting,
今すぐ 会いたいよ
I want to see you right now.
泣きたくなるような Moonlight
Moonlight that makes me want to cry,
電話もできない Midnight
Midnight where I can't even call.
だって純情 どうしよう
Because I'm so innocent, what should I do?
ハートは万華鏡
My heart is a kaleidoscope.
月の光に 導かれ
Guided by the moonlight,
何度も 巡りあう
We'll meet again and again.
星座のまたたき数え
Counting the twinkling of the constellations,
占う恋の行方
I divine the future of our love.
同じ地球に生まれたの
We were born on the same planet,
ミラクル・ロマンス
Miracle Romance.
もいちど ふたりで Weekend
Once more, a weekend for just the two of us,
神様かなえて Happy-end
God, grant us a happy ending.
現在・過去・未来も
In the present, past, and future,
あなたに首ったけ
I'm head over heels for you.
出会った時の 懐かしい
The nostalgic feeling of when we first met,
まなざし 忘れない
I won't forget that look.
幾千万の星から
Out of millions of stars,
あなたを見つけられる
I can find you.
偶然もチャンスに変える
Even turning coincidences into chances,
生き方が好きよ
I love that way of living.
不思議な奇跡クロスして
Wondrous miracles crossing paths,
何度も 巡りあう
We'll meet again and again.
星座のまたたき数え
Counting the twinkling of the constellations,
占う恋の行方
I divine the future of our love.
同じ地球に生まれたの
We were born on the same planet,
ミラクル・ロマンス
Miracle Romance.
信じているの
I believe in it,
ミラクル・ロマンス
Miracle Romance.
2年生 パカはひとり ここの街の 空見上げる
A second-year student, all alone, looking up at
the sky in this town.
サボり勝手 パジャマ着てる 夏休みが 来ずに中退
Skipping as I please, wearing pajamas,
dropping out before summer vacation comes.
地球で 宇宙人なって 大人になっても 宇宙の
Becoming an alien on Earth, even as an adult,
the universe's...
待ち合わせ室には もっと変な あなたがいたの
...waiting room had someone even stranger,
and that was you.
受信してるかなと 接続してみると
Wondering if you're receiving, when I try to
connect,
みんなが避ける中で パチクリ見ている あなたがいたから
In the midst of everyone avoiding me,
there you were, looking with wide eyes.
テレパシー 気持ちが 電波が違くても
Even if our telepathic feelings and radio waves
are different,
きっと
Surely.
きっとね 何か
I'm sure you've
掴んでくれてる
grasped something...
あなたのことが 好き
I love you.
（ルルル…）
(Lu lu lu...)
こんな不安定
So unstable,
バイトできない
I can't do a part-time job,
会話できない
I can't have a conversation,
空見上げる
I look up at the sky.
サボリ爆ぜ
Blowing off work,
パジャマ着てる
wearing pajamas,
夏休みが
before summer vacation
来ずに 中退
even starts, dropping out.
社会で 宇宙人なんて
In society, an alien...
あなたの手も 宇宙の
your hand too... space's...
待ち合わせ室で めまい
In the waiting room, dizziness...
また 巡り会えるよね
we'll meet again, right?
愛してくれるかなと
I wonder if you'll love me...
狂ったり してみようと
let's try going a bit crazy.
みんなが 避ける中で
While everyone was avoiding me,
パチクリ見ている あなたがいたから
you were there, watching with wide eyes.
テレパシー
Telepathic
気持ちが
feelings...
電波が 近くても
even if the radio waves are close.
きっとね 何か
I'm sure you've
掴んでくれてる
grasped something...
あなたのことが 好き
I love you.
（ルルル…）
(Lu lu lu...)
受信して くれるのかなと
I wonder if you'll receive it...
心配も してるんです
I'm worried too.
なんだかんだで そばにいてくれてる
After everything, I love you
あなたが 好き
for being by my side.
そんなあなたのことが好き
I love you just as you are.
そんなあなたのことが好きなんです
I really love you just as you are.
ああ あなたのことが好き
Ah, I love you.
そんなあなたのことが好き
I love you just as you are.
きっと あなたしか
I'm sure only you
受信 できないの
can receive it.
3 2 1
ケロッ！ケロッ！ケロッ！ いざ進め〜ッ
Kero! Kero! Kero! Advance now!
地球侵略せよ
Invade the Earth!
ケッケロッケロ〜！
Ke-kero-kero!
傘持って
On days I take
出かけた日には
an umbrella,
いつも晴れ
it's always sunny!
「気をつけ〜ッ、目を食いしばれッ！」
"Attention! Keep your eyes peeled!"
カレーのライスを炊き忘れ
Forgot to cook the rice for the curry.
閉まるドア
Closing door
小指はさんだ
pinched my pinky.
飛び乗ったら
Jumped on and it was
行き先ちがう
the wrong direction.
社員旅行はケロン
The company trip is to Keron.
あ、買った方が安いね晩のおかずッ！
Ah, it's cheaper to buy tonight's side dish!
ピロッ！ピロッ！ピロッ！ 突撃は〜ッ
Piro! Piro! Piro! Charge ahead
動く歩道で行け
on a moving walkway!
ピッピロッピロ〜！
Pi-piro-piro!
早寝して
Sleep early,
寝坊して
oversleep,
また二度寝する
then sleep in again!
「全体〜ッ、止まれッ！ 回れ、お手ッ！」
"Company, halt! Turn around, paw!"
嫌われたいのに愛される
I want to be hated, yet I'm loved.
いらないもの買った大バーゲン
Bought useless stuff at a big sale.
ほしいものあるとお金がない
When I want something, I have no money.
四の五の言えよケロン
Say four or five things, Keron.
あ、カミナリ鳴っても隠すヘソがないッ！！！
Ah, even when thunder rolls, I have no belly button to hide!
熱きこの血潮と
This hot blood and
胸に刻まれし闘魂
the fighting spirit carved in our chests.
永遠に勝ち誇れ
Glory in victory forever,
我らがケロン！
our Keron!
熱きこの血潮と
This hot blood and
胸に刻まれし闘魂
the fighting spirit carved in our chests.
永遠に勝ち誇れ
Glory in victory forever,
愛しき星よ！
beloved star!
我らがケロン！
Our Keron!
「全体〜ッ、止まっちゃダメッ！！！」
"Company, don't you dare stop!!!"
水かき汗かき
Webbed feet, sweating
べそっかき
Crying face
歯みがきならイチゴの香り
If you brush your teeth, it smells like strawberry
ケロンは宇宙一、たぶん
Keronians are the best in the universe, probably
あ、駅から5分は実は15分!!!
Ah, "5 minutes from the station" is actually 15 minutes!!!
それじゃーソルジャー
Well then, soldier
ど疲れさんッ!!
Good work!!
ケロッケロッ
Ribbit ribbit
ケロッ!!
Ribbit!!
ケロッ!!!
Ribbit!!!
UFO
手を合わせて見つめるだけで
Just by clasping hands and looking at each other
愛し合える話もできず
Not even being able to talk about our love
くちづけするより甘く
Sweeter than a kiss
ささやき聞くより強く
Stronger than hearing a whisper
私の心をゆさぶるあなた
You, who shakes my heart
ものいわずにおどってみせて
Show me your dance without saying a word
すぐにあなたに分かってしまう
You'll understand right away
飲みたくなったらお酒
If you want to drink, then alcohol
寝たくなったらベッド
If you want to sleep, then a bed
次から次へとさし出すあなた
You, who offers one thing after another
信じられないことばかりあるの
There are only unbelievable things
もしかしたら もしかしたら そうなのかしら
Could it be, could it be, is it so?
それでもいいわ 近頃少し
That's fine too, lately a bit...
地球の男にあきたところよ
I've grown tired of men on Earth
あーっ!
Ah!
でも私は確かめたいわ
But I want to make sure
その素顔を一度は見たい
I want to see your true face at least once
かがみにうつしてみたり
Trying to reflect in a mirror
光をあててみたり
Trying to shine light on it
それでもあなたは普通のあなた
But you're just a normal person
ああ突然オレンジ色の
Ah, suddenly an orange...
ああ光が私をつつみ
Ah, light envelops me
夢みる気持ちにさせて どこかへさらってゆくわ
Making me feel like I'm dreaming, carrying me away somewhere
やっぱりそうなのすてきなあなた
I knew it, you're wonderful
信じられないことでしょうけれど
It's unbelievable, I'm sure
うそじゃないの うそじゃないの 本当のことよ
It's not a lie, it's not a lie, it's the truth
それでもいいわ 近頃少し
That's fine too, lately a bit...
地球の男にあきたところよ
I've grown tired of men on Earth
あーっ!
Ah!
僕らの生まれてくるずっとずっと前にはもう
Long, long before we were born...
アポロ11号は月に行ったっていうのに
Apollo 11 had already gone to the moon
アポロ
Apollo
みんなが手に入れられる限定の
A limited edition that everyone can get
君の腕時計はデジタル仕様
Your wristwatch is a digital type
それで僕のより早く進むって本当かい? 多分 壊れてる
Is it true that it goes faster than mine? It's probably broken
空を覆う巨大な広告塔には
On the giant billboard covering the sky...
美人以外にあり得ない微笑
A smile that can only belong to a beauty
赤い 赤い 口紅でさ
With red, red lipstick
僕らの生まれてくる ずっとずっと前にはもう
Long, long before we were even born
アポロ11号は月に行ったっていうのに
Apollo 11 had already gone to the moon
僕らはこの街がまだ ジャングルだった頃から
While we've been around since this town was still a jungle
変わらない愛の形 探してる
Still searching for the same unchanging form of love
大統領の名前なんてさ 覚えてなくてもね いいけれど
It's okay if you don't even remember the president's name, but
せめて自分の信じてた 夢くらいはどうにか 覚えていて
At least try to remember your own dreams you once believed in
思考を巡る情報に 振り回されるのは ビジョンが曖昧なんでしょう
Getting tossed around by thoughts and information must be because your vision is blurred
頭ン中バグっちゃってさ
Your head's all glitched out
僕らの生まれてくる もっともっと前にはもう
Long, long before we were even born
アポロ計画は 始動していたんだろう
The Apollo Project had already been set in motion
本気で月に行こうって考えたんだろうね
They must have seriously considered going to the moon
なんだか愛の理想みたいだね
It's kind of like the ideal of love
このままのスピードで 世界が回ったら
If the world keeps spinning at this same speed
アポロ100号はどこまで行けるんだろう
How far will Apollo 100 be able to go?
離ればなれになった 悲しい恋人たちの
The long-distance call from the sad, separated lovers
長いメロム ビーナスなんて素敵ね
To Venus, it sounds so lovely
僕らの生まれてくる ずっとずっと前にはもう
Long, long before we were even born
アポロ11号は月に行ったっていうのに
Apollo 11 had already gone to the moon
僕らはこの街がまだ ジャングルだった頃から
While we've been around since this town was still a jungle
変わらない愛の形 探してる
Still searching for the same unchanging form of love
うなーい！
Luna-i!
この後は4周年記念グッズのおしらせがあるならい！
Next up, I have an announcement about my 4th Anniversary Goods!
活動4周年記念
4th Anniversary Celebration
ででーん！1つ目はこちら！
Tada! The first one is this!
「ムーンギャラクシーアクリルジオラマスタンド」なのら！
It's the "Moon Galaxy Acrylic Diorama Stand"!
●ムーンギャラクシーアクリルジオラマスタンド●
●Moon Galaxy Acrylic Diorama Stand●
今回の宇宙や月や星をテーマに かんざきぱぱに描き下ろしていただきました
Kanzaki-papa drew this based on this year's themes of space, the moon, and stars
ルーナイトがはしごを登ってるのが可愛いのら
The Lu-Knight climbing the ladder is so cute
そして、2つ目はこちら！
And the second one is this!
「ルーナのおめめのアイマスク」なのら！
It's "Luna's Eyes Eye Mask"!
★ルーナのおめめのアイマスク★
★Luna's Eyes Eye Mask★
お口がちょっと空いてる可愛い表情のんなたんなのら
It's Luna with a cute expression and her mouth slightly open
アイマスクとして使うもよし 机の上に置いておくだけでもんなたんと おめめが合うのらね
You can use it as an eye mask, or just leave it on your desk to catch Luna's eye
そして、3つ目はこちら！
And the third one is this!
「ルーナの2WAYネックピロー」なのら！
It's "Luna's 2WAY Neck Pillow"!
★ルーナの2WAYネックピロー★
★Luna's 2WAY Neck Pillow★
こちらはクッションとネックピローで 2種類使い分けができるのら
You can use it in two ways: as a cushion or a neck pillow
どっちの状態でもんなたんがふんだんに 散りばめられてるのらよ
In either mode, there's Luna's face scattered all over it
ルーナのおめめのアイマスクと 合わせてお部屋で使ってほしいのら
I hope you use it in your room along with the Eye Mask
そして、4つ目はこちら！
And the fourth one is this!
「ルーナの4周年記念Tシャツ」なのら！
It's "Luna's 4th Anniversary T-shirt"!
★ルーナの4周年記念Tシャツ★
★Luna's 4th Anniversary T-shirt★
袖にピンクのポイントカラーと 王冠と文字のシンプルデザインに 作ったので...
I made it with a pink accent color on the sleeves and a simple crown and text design...
どこへでも着やすいかなと思うのら。
I think it's easy to wear anywhere.
2023年の誕生日グッズでルーナイトパーカーを作ったので、
We made a Lunaite hoodie for my 2023 birthday merch,
合わせて着てくれたら嬉しいのら。
so I'd be happy if you wore them together.
最後に、フルセット購入してくれた全員に...
Finally, for everyone who purchases the full set...
直筆サイン入りのポストカードが付いてきます。
...it comes with a hand-signed postcard.
箔押し複製メッセージも読んでなのらね。
Please read the foil-stamped duplicate message, too.
4周年記念グッズはこの後21時から、
The 4th-anniversary merch will be available starting at 21:00,
ホロライブのオフィシャルショップにて販売されるのら。
at the Hololive Official Shop.
この後SNSの方でもお知らせもします。
I'll also announce it on SNS after this.
またこの配信の概要欄にも記載しておくので、
It's also listed in the description of this stream,
ぜひぜひ購入して、みんなのお家にうなたんを置いてほしいのらよ。
so please buy it and keep a 'Unatan' at home.
みんな、ここまで見てくれてありがとのら！
Everyone, thank you for watching this far!
もう一回アナウンスするけど、
I'll announce it one more time,
この後『ぐるぐる回るまわる〜』のMVが公開されるので、
the MV for 'Guru Guru Mawaru Mawaru' will be released after this,
みんな、見てなのらね〜。
so everyone, please watch it.
みんな見てね！ 忘れちゃだめなのらよ〜。
Please watch it! Don't forget it!
よし！最後は今日来てくれたゲストのみんなと歌って、
Alright! Finally, I'll sing with all the guests who came today,
宇宙の彼方に旅立つのら！
and we'll depart to the edge of the universe!
出発〜！
Departure!
うお〜！ / いけ〜！
Whoa! / Let's go!
さらば地球よ
Farewell, Earth
旅立つ船は
The ship setting sail
宇宙戦艦
Is the Space Battleship
ヤマト
Yamato
宇宙の彼方 イスカンダルへ
To the edge of the universe, to Iscandar
運命背負い 今旅立つ
Shouldering fate, we depart now
必ずここへ
That we will surely
帰って来ると
Return here
手を振る人に
To the people waving hands
笑顔で応え
We respond with a smile
銀河を離れ イスカンダルへ
Leaving the galaxy, heading for Iscandar
はるばるのぞむ
Looking from afar
宇宙戦艦ヤマト
Space Battleship Yamato
さらば地球よ
Farewell, Earth
愛する人よ
My beloved
宇宙戦艦
Space Battleship
ヤマト
Yamato
地球を救う 使命を帯びて
Charged with the mission to save Earth
戦う男 燃えるロマン
The fighting man, burning romance
誰かがこれを やらねばならぬ
Someone has to do this
期待の人が 俺たちならば
If we are the ones expected
銀河を離れ イスカンダルへ
Leaving the galaxy, heading for Iscandar
はるばるのぞむ
Looking from afar
宇宙戦艦ヤマト
Space Battleship Yamato
発進！
Blast off!
【Moon Galaxy 4th Anniversary 3D LIVE !!】
カバー株式会社
COVER Corp.
振付制作：まいどん（おでんガールズ）
Choreography: Maidon (Oden Girls)
3D制作：kanauru
3D Production: kanauru
彩色：紺色。（スタジオイマジネ）
Color: Kon'iro (Studio Imgine)
背景：みさわさくら。 まるまる。 しるかみ 鉄瓶
Background: Misawa Sakura, Marumaru,
Shirukami, Tetsubin
楽曲制作：Symny ればん 山本こーすけ esP526 クリスP
クックルP 犬猿 マッチ 日南めい まつこ KosK
Music Production: Symny, Reban, Yamamoto Kosuke,
esP526, ChrisP, CuckoolP, Inuzaru, Match,
Hinami Mei, Matsuko, KosK
楽曲MIX：中山太陽
Music MIX: Nakayama Taiyo
企画：姫森ルーナ
Planning: Himemori Luna
総合演出：姫森ルーナ
General Direction: Himemori Luna
協力：カバー株式会社 ルーナイト達
Cooperation: COVER Corp., Lu-Knights
監督：姫森ルーナ
Supervision: Himemori Luna
4周年記念ライブ見てくれてありがと〜! ❤️
Thank you for watching the 4th Anniversary LIVE! ❤️
いつもルーナイトがそばに居てくれるから
んなんなに頑張れてるのら!!
I can work this hard because the Lu-Knights
are always by my side!!
どうか姫森ルーナのこれからも
ルーナイトに見届けてほしいのら!!
Please continue to watch over Himemori Luna
from now on too!!
大好きなのらよ❤️ ちゅっ❤️ ばいばー❤️ (ooo ror)
I love you all! ❤️ *kiss* ❤️ Bye-bye! ❤️ (ooo ror)